Hey I think it's near enough court to so
嘿，我认为法院就在附近
I'll start so this talk is is Jakarta EE
我开始说的就是雅加达EE
relevant to IOT so the answer in my
与物联网有关，所以我的答案
views is yes
意见是
what's the end of the talk so welcome to
演讲结束了，所以欢迎您
is describe a use case that you could
描述一个您可以使用的用例
use for IOT in and using Jakarta EE I
在和使用Jakarta EE I中用于IOT
then have a demonstration setup which
然后进行演示设置
are managed to get working a last minute
设法在最后一分钟开始工作
after forgetting my power supplies and
忘记我的电源后
then we'll go through basically the code
然后我们将基本上通过代码
that builds the demonstration so just
建立示范，所以
looking at code snippets from Jakarta EE
查看来自Jakarta EE的代码片段
and showing how that sort of builds
并展示这种建造方式
builds what we're showing for a desk
构建我们要在办公桌上显示的内容
here locally it's a small room so you'll
在当地，这是一个小房间，所以你会
be able to see so this is this is a
能够看到，所以这是一个
demonstration that we have set up it's
我们已经建立的示范
basically we try to show that using
基本上，我们试图证明使用
Jakarta EE you can actually build both
Jakarta EE实际上可以同时构建
on the device and scaling right up into
在设备上并向上扩展到
a cloud type environment so using
云类型的环境，因此使用
exactly the same technology using
使用完全相同的技术
exactly the same runtimes and using the
完全相同的运行时，并使用
same sort of coding style so what we
同样的编码风格，所以我们
have here we have a sensor node
在这里，我们有一个传感器节点
basically for that we're running on
基本上是因为我们正在
raspberry PI's so there's a rath loop I
覆盆子PI，所以有一个循环循环
sense a node here that's running has a
感觉这里正在运行的节点有一个
sense hat on which has a humidity sensor
带有湿度传感器的感应帽
built into it so that that's running
内置于其中，以便运行
basically generating measurements of
基本上产生测量
humidity in the room at the moment and
此刻房间的湿度和
thats networked with through a switch to
多数民众赞成通过切换到网络
another raspberry pi here which is
这里的另一个树莓派是
acting like a gateway Nogrady to take
充当网关Nogrady采取
samples from the network
来自网络的样本
and it has an embedded web application
它具有嵌入式Web应用程序
which you can view in measure humidity
您可以查看以测量湿度
and they're connected using Tecate II so
他们使用Tecate II连接在一起
they are running on a PI or micro which
他们在PI或Micro上运行
we'll come to which is a runtime that
我们将来到一个运行时
supports two car te AP ice or Java EE AP
支持两个车载AP Ice或Java EE AP
ice and these things are communicating
冰和这些东西正在交流
by sending Network events between them
通过在它们之间发送网络事件
so they're using what's called CDI and
所以他们使用所谓的CDI和
they're sending clustered events between
他们正在之间发送群集事件
one node and the other node so that
一个节点，另一个节点，这样
application that's running is using
正在运行的应用程序正在使用
WebSockets so mr. Carter uh obviously
WebSockets先生。卡特恩
you get a full range of web api's and
您可以获得完整的Web API，并且
that includes the web socket API so
包括Web套接字API，因此
that's pushing data and real-time down
推动数据和实时下降
to a browser so and that updates
到浏览器，以便更新
effectively graph using html5 in real
有效地使用html5图形
time and again that's currently running
一次又一次正在运行
on Raspberry Pi and we should be able to
在Raspberry Pi上，我们应该能够
get it on the machine as well on the
也可以在机器上
laptop and then for this demonstration
笔记本电脑，然后进行此演示
we also have what what's marked on there
我们那里也有什么标记
as a cloud connector in this case it's
作为这种情况下的云连接器
not if we're going to scale up the cloud
如果我们要扩大云规模的话
we will that we also do a demo that
我们将做一个演示，
includes Microsoft Azure but for this
包括Microsoft Azure，但为此
purposes what we're doing we have used a
目的是我们在做什么，我们已经使用了
MQTT connector and we're pushing MQTT
MQTT连接器，我们正在推动MQTT
events so in this case the connector is
事件，因此在这种情况下，连接器是
going to be using MQTT to send mqtt
将使用MQTT发送mqtt
messages onto my laptop okay it uses a
消息到我的笔记本电脑上，好吧，它使用了
standard standard in Java EE JCA which
Java EE JCA中的标准标准
sounds the Java connector connector
听起来Java连接器连接器
architecture or API which is a standard
标准的架构或API
way to build connectors to other other
建立与其他连接器的方式
systems that out sort of not inherent or
并非是固有的或
not supported directly in
不直接支持
in delray so for example in this case we
在delray中，例如在这种情况下，
have very connected to the MQTT
与MQTT的联系非常紧密
messaging protocol okay
消息协议还可以
event we haven't got in demonstration is
我们没有示范的事件是
beyond that you could then use once the
除此之外，您可以使用一次
messages were off the Gateway node you
消息不在您的网关节点上
can obviously then push them into on the
显然可以然后将它们推入
on the cloud side into any cloud
在云方面到任何云
infrastructure build up big data grids
基础架构建立大数据网格
and use all the standard enterprise
并使用所有标准企业
technology that to cut it you each are
每个人都可以削减的技术
very ease renowned for to you know to
很容易以您知道而闻名
build a data visualization or data
建立数据可视化或数据
capture system for users okay so what
用户捕获系统好吗
we're running on here obviously most
我们显然在这里跑
people would think that running Java EE
人们会认为运行Java EE
on IOT is of the answers no these things
在物联网上的答案是没有这些东西
are big fat heavy weight application
大脂肪重应用
servers that use gigabytes of memory you
使用千兆字节内存的服务器
know they're gigabytes in size to
知道它们的大小为千兆字节
install well that's basically not true I
安装好，这基本上是不正确的我
mean that is what it was like maybe ten
就是那大概十
years ago but not not in this day and
年前但不是今天
age really so we're running power micro
真的很老化，所以我们正在运行微型电源
so I'm from Paora I'm Steve millage so I
我来自Paora，我叫Steve Millage，所以我
found the payara and part micro is a
发现payara和部分微是一个
really small runtime so we desert we
运行时间非常短，所以我们放弃了
designed it to be very simple so there's
设计得非常简单，所以
no installation you don't have to set up
无需安装，无需安装
an installation download a gigabytes of
安装下载千兆字节的
data do lots of messing around it
数据使周围充满混乱
effectively you just run it on the
实际上，您只需在
command line and it on bootstrap a
命令行，它在引导程序上
Jakarta ye java re' runtime that
Jakarta ye Java re'runtime
supports standard java applications so
支持标准的Java应用程序，因此
it's pretty small jar file it says less
这是一个很小的jar文件，它说的更少
than 70 Meg and we keep trying to keep
超过70兆，我们一直在努力保持
it down there we're very close to 70
它在那边，我们非常接近70
mega
兆
we'll keep trying to get it down so that
我们将继续努力降低它，以便
each slices drive change the slides and
每个切片驱动器更改幻灯片和
it's based on the full PI or a server
它基于完整的PI或服务器
which eventually which originally was
最终是最初的
based off grassfish so it is a full
基于草鱼，所以很饱
application server and we have users
应用服务器，我们有用户
that are using them from very small
从很小的角度使用它们
devices right up to you know hundred no
取决于您的设备百无
clusters building data grids on the
在建筑物上建立数据网格的集群
cloud so you
云让你
and on the heaps usage or how you set up
以及堆的用法或设置方式
the heat you can obviously scale to very
热量显然可以扩展到
large applications as well and we
大型应用程序以及
basically have done a lot of work with
基本上已经做了很多工作
some customers to make this design for
一些客户为此进行设计
cloud environments so that it's elastic
云环境，使其具有弹性
and also to make it for container
并使其成为容器
environment so that it has a lot of
环境，所以它有很多
capabilities in there to work in in
在那里工作的能力
containers including things like support
包含支持之类的容器
for environment variable replacement as
用于环境变量替换为
you move I contain it from one
你移动我从一个包含它
environment to the next you can change
下一个环境可以改变
things like database URLs those sort of
诸如数据库URL之类的东西
things but it's also I say pretty small
东西，但我也说很小
so to run it you basically take the jar
所以要运行它，基本上是拿罐子
file you run - jar pie or micro jar and
您运行的文件-罐子馅饼或微型罐子和
then deploy what would be a standard
然后部署将是一个标准
java ee deployment artifact so this is
java ee部署工件，所以这是
what's happening on on these devices so
这些设备上发生了什么
on this one we just have we have an EJB
在这一点上，我们只有一个EJB
so you know people don't think that
所以你知道人们不认为
people still use agb's but it's very
人们仍然使用agb，但是
scrapped powerful technology and this is
报废了强大的技术，这是
basically running an EJB tiny beam that
基本上运行一个EJB细光束
measures a sensor and also pushes out to
测量传感器，然后将其推出
the frame buffer which is these picks
这些选择的帧缓冲区
mutual these LEDs on the front it does
这些LED相互在前面做
that on a time basis it's using
在时间上它正在使用
internally some of the code from your
内部来自您的一些代码
attack but does the GPIO work to access
攻击，但GPIO是否可以访问
the GPIO on the Raspberry Pi so it's
Raspberry Pi上的GPIO，因此
taking Eurotech code from the koomer
从koomer那里获取Eurotech代码
project I believe hacking it around a
我相信这个项目
bit to get rid of all the camel stuff
摆脱所有骆驼的东西
and just go and working directly on GPIO
然后直接在GPIO上工作
since so and there's oh that's ran
从那以后，还有哦，那跑了
essentially just as Empire a micro jar
本质上就像帝国的微型罐子
like that so like say so what we have we
像这样说所以我们有什么
have one micro here running an EJB it's
这里有一个运行EJB的微型计算机
measuring the sensors from humidity we
从湿度测量传感器
have another PI R here running an
在这里运行另一个PI R
embedded browser
嵌入式浏览器
there on on raspberry pies and you'd be
在树莓派上，你会
able to see from there but if I
能够从那里看到，但如果我
effectively blow one here you can see
有效地吹一个你可以看到
that obviously the humidity measurement
显然湿度测量
has gone up so I can actually put that
已经上升，所以我实际上可以
on the screen I can remember the horror
在屏幕上，我可以记得恐怖
why didn't I remember okay so that's the
我为什么不记得好，那是
same basically accessing the brightly
基本上基本上都是一样
shakaar te runtime running on the on the
shakaar te运行时在
raspberry pi so again if I and that you
覆盆子pi所以如果我和你又
can see that that it's generating the
可以看到它正在生成
data okay so also attempted to run add a
数据还可以，所以还尝试运行添加一个
console on here but it's not something
控制台在这里，但没什么
working that isn't going to work so what
工作是行不通的，那又怎样
I wanted to show was that actually these
我想证明的是，实际上这些
are really small so the heap size so I
真的很小，所以堆大小，所以我
was trying to X across from my raspberry
试图从我的树莓对面X
pi to 4 and a console on the laptop with
pi到4和笔记本电脑上的控制台
us not refreshing crop it so the pie
我们不刷新它，所以馅饼
maker like say is running in about to do
像说的制造商正在做
this this sensor is running about forty
这个传感器运行约四十
forty megabytes of heat so it's not
四十兆字节的热量，所以不是
generating a huge you know load or
产生巨大的负载，或者
impact on the Raspberry Pi I know that
我对Raspberry Pi的影响
they're quite large devices in the IOT
它们是物联网中的大型设备
world but it's plenty small enough to
世界，但足够小
run
跑
on there so any questions on setup
在那里，所以任何关于设置的问题
before I sort of have briefly look at
在我简要介绍一下之前
some of the code involved so Mike said
一些代码涉及，所以迈克说
hey are micro itself is a runtime that
嘿，微本身就是一个运行时
supports the vast majority of while our
支持绝大多数
java ee api is so it covers it covers
java ee api涵盖了它
all the web api's it covers GE JB's and
所有的网络api都涵盖了GE JB和
what we have running on the sensor is a
我们在传感器上运行的是
simple singleton egb timer so the code
简单的单例egb计时器，所以代码
is pretty simple
很简单
so we have a schedule on the EJB so on
所以我们有一个关于EJB的时间表
there which is basically running running
那里基本上是跑步
every second and that is running that
每一秒都在运行
basically a tiny small piece of code
基本上是一小段代码
which is creating a new measurement and
这正在创建一个新的衡量标准，
it's talking to the sensor itself to get
它正在与传感器本身交谈以获取
that measurement and again like I said
像我说的那样
that that code is some of the Eurotech
该代码是Eurotech的一部分
raspberry pi code to interface to the
树莓派代码以连接到
sense hat it does that and then from the
感觉帽子做到这一点，然后从
network perspective it's using a
从网络角度来看，
specific feature of higher on my PI or
我的PI上较高的特定功能或
micro which is an extension to CDI CDI
micro是CDI CDI的扩展
is component dependency injection but it
是组件依赖注入，但它
supports events and Perl micro has an
支持事件，Perl micro具有
extension to that which supports events
支持事件的扩展
across the network okay so this outbound
跨网络还可以，所以这个出站
annotation tells the PI or a runtime
注释告诉PI或运行时
that this this event that I might fire
我可能会触发的这个事件
needs to be spread around the network
需要在网络中传播
and then it buyers you vent there in
然后你向那里的买家发泄
that line of code and then that's gone
那行代码，然后就消失了
that's all the code is to measure the
这就是所有代码来衡量
actual
实际
[Music]
[音乐]
humidity and that's essentially the
湿度，这实际上是
application that's running on that black
黑色运行的应用程序
raspberry pi just it hasn't it slightly
树莓派只是没有
slightly bit more code just to drive the
多一点的代码只是为了驱动
display for demo purposes so it just
出于演示目的而显示，因此
sends a basically a string out to a
发送一个基本的字符串到
frame buffer then say on this Raspberry
然后在此Raspberry上说帧缓冲区
Pi we have a couple of applications
Pi，我们有两个应用程序
running one of them is if is a full web
运行其中之一是如果是完整的网络
application that's driving the lately
最近正在推动的应用程序
graph and again they say because it
图，他们又说，因为它
because running Java EE we don't have to
因为运行Java EE，我们不必
you know use any different special API
你知道使用任何其他特殊的API
is just to generate these web
只是为了产生这些网站
applications on on the small device so
小型设备上的应用程序
it's a WebSocket application so it has a
这是一个WebSocket应用程序，所以它有一个
special annotation to declare that which
特殊注释来声明
is rent point which is the graph when
是租金点，是图时
the browser connects to the web
浏览器连接到网络
application the on open method is
应用程序的打开方法是
initiated and that's just basically
启动，这基本上是
registering that there's a browser on
注册有一个浏览器
the session so when we have sector when
会议，所以当我们有部门的时候
we have two of them then it just keep
我们有两个，那就继续
track that there's two connections to
跟踪有两个连接
WebSocket connections and then we have
WebSocket连接，然后我们有
this method here you can see it so what
这种方法在这里你可以看到它怎么办
this is this is observing events off the
这是观察事件
network so it has the observed
网络，因此它具有观察
lamentation which is standard Java EE
哀叹，这是标准的Java EE
which has observed networks of the
观察到了
basically sort of observed events of the
基本上是观察到的事件
type a humidity measurement and then
输入湿度测量值，然后
this inbound just says it basically
这个入站基本上就是说
sucks those events off the network okay
将那些事件从网络上清除掉
when she gets an event it basically
当她得到一个事件时，基本上
loops through each session and pushes
遍历每个会话并推送
down the WebSocket
向下的WebSocket
pushes down the WebSocket JSON string
下推WebSocket JSON字符串
that represents the data from the
代表来自
humidity sensor okay so again all that's
湿度传感器好吧，再说一遍
all that api's are all standard so
所有的api都是标准的
they're all standard standard api is in
它们都是标准的标准api
java ee so you can build these
java ee，所以您可以构建这些
applications quite rapidly and then
应用程序然后迅速
obviously generates the graph so the
显然会生成图形，因此
graph is html5
图是html5
it's an html5 graphing component which
这是一个html5图形组件
is that pretty standard and when it gets
那是很标准的，什么时候得到
a JSON string it'll basically and that
一个JSON字符串，基本上
essentially becomes you know that's push
本质上变成了你知道的推动
pushes the day to day ok any care of
每天都可以
questions on that no - ok so in addition
关于不的问题-好的，此外
on this what we call the Gateway node we
在此我们称为网关节点
have another application running in a
在另一个应用程序中运行
separate PI or micro so these are like
单独的PI或微型，所以就像
little micro services and that is doing
小微服务，这正在做
the connection to the cloud so this is
与云的连接，所以这是
or in this case connecting to MQTT
或者在这种情况下连接到MQTT
broker which is running on my laptop so
经纪人正在我的笔记本电脑上运行
again this is using again standard Java
再次使用标准Java
EE we have a project in PI aura called
EE，我们在PI Aura中有一个名为
cloud connectors which has built a bunch
云连接器已经建立了一堆
of connectors to messaging systems that
消息系统的连接器
aren't JMS which would be the standard
不是JMS，这将是标准
Java EE so we have one for MQTT we have
Java EE，所以我们有一个MQTT
from one for a sewer service bus Apache
从一个下水道服务总线Apache
calf calf car and I was an SQ s simple
小牛小牛车，我是SQ的简单
queue service so you can get the data
队列服务，以便您获取数据
into the cloud quite easily using these
使用这些工具很容易地进入云
connectors and so there has a bunch of
连接器，所以有一堆
metadata and annotations which is
元数据和注释是
defining what's called a connection
定义所谓的连接
factory so this is shows you basically
工厂，所以这基本上告诉你
there's also adapted as what Weald what
还有改编成什么Weald What
we deploy which is a standard component
我们部署这是一个标准组件
from payara you have a MQTT connection
从payara，您有MQTT连接
factory and then there is the mqtt
工厂，然后有mqtt
properties so I've got the server URI
属性，所以我有服务器URI
okay then when we receive one of these
好吧，当我们收到其中之一
messages again so we haven't observes
消息再次，所以我们没有观察到
again inbound so when we get one of
再次入站，所以当我们得到一个
these Network events in this
这些网络事件
micro-service it uses the connection
它使用连接的微服务
factory and basically takes the
工厂，基本上需要
measurement writes it to a byte array
测量将其写入字节数组
then pushes it out to mqtt with the
然后将其推出给mqtt
publish on the test test topic okay and
在测试主题上发布测试还可以，
then on this laptop I have if you can
然后在这台笔记本电脑上，如果可以的话
see it but I have again another micro
看到它，但我又有另一个微
service which is listening on that MQTT
正在监听该MQTT的服务
topic using Java EE and the MQTT
Java EE和MQTT主题
connector and printing out the message
连接器并打印出消息
like I don't know why I'm using this one
就像我不知道为什么要用这个
for
对于
okay so you can see the value there 51
好，这样您就可以看到其中的值51
and if I told them that again hopefully
如果我告诉他们希望
should go up okay this is on 64 at the
应该上升好吧，这是在64
minute so that's basically just again a
分钟，基本上基本上又是
tiny micro servers pulling and the mqtt
微型服务器拉动和mqtt
messages from mosquito running on my
蚊子在我身上运行的消息
laptop so that's that's again pushing
笔记本电脑，这就是再次推动
out so this this guy is pushing out the
出来，所以这个家伙正在推出
events onto a mosquito broker running on
事件进入正在运行的蚊子中介
my Linux laptop okay so so like say we
我的Linux笔记本电脑还可以，所以说我们
have a project on Paora which is
在Paora上有一个项目
building these connectors for Java EE
为Java EE构建这些连接器
the memory let's say we have on for
内存让我们说
Kafka sqs service Boston MQTT so these
Kafka sqs服务波士顿MQTT，所以这些
connectors are standard what I call JCA
连接器是标准的，我称之为JCA
connectors they should work on other
他们应该在其他上工作的连接器
Java you runtimes like wildfire and they
Java您像野火一样运行时，它们
are pushing their basic available to use
正在推动其基本可用
to get data off these devices attention
从这些设备上获取数据
straight into the cloud and things like
直接进入云端，诸如此类
that
那
that's just an example we have done it
那只是我们做的一个例子
in the past to service bus but I didn't
过去去公车，但我没有
want to rely on the network to push it
想依靠网络来推动它
out to the cloud so once you've got data
迁移到云中，因此一旦获得数据
off the IOT device these PI are a micro
在物联网设备上，这些PI是微型的
in Jakarta II you can actually then
在雅加达二世，您实际上可以
exactly the same API is exactly the same
完全相同的API完全相同
programming knowledge that you have to
您必须具备的编程知识
then build out the server side as well
然后也建立服务器端
so you can use the same PI R micros
因此您可以使用相同的PI R micros
these two are clustered together so
这两个聚集在一起
that's how the events are flying between
这就是事件之间发生的方式
them so even on on the raspberry PI's
他们甚至在树莓派的
they're clustering and sharing data
他们正在聚集和共享数据
you could then on the cloud you can
然后您可以在云上
scale that out to a massive Multi multi
将其扩展为大规模的Multi multi
gigabyte in-memory datastore if you
千兆内存数据存储（如果您）
wanted to but exactly the sort of same
想要但完全一样
technology the same api's so it would be
技术相同的api，因此
possible to build you know to scale out
可能建立您知道的横向扩展
many hundreds of these going through the
其中数百个正在经历
gateway node and then pushing data up to
网关节点，然后将数据推送到
a cloud environment and using the same
云环境并使用相同的环境
power and micros to store that within a
功率和微分将其存储在
in-memory data grid so if we did that on
内存中的数据网格，所以如果我们这样做
the this is code that would be shown
这是将显示的代码
four on this on the cloud side this is
在云这边的四个是
the code that would be used to actually
实际将使用的代码
retrieve data and push it into a data
检索数据并将其推入数据
grid so the data grid is an in-memory
网格，因此数据网格是内存中的
key value store so you could say cluster
键值存储，所以您可以说集群
all the payara micros up and then store
所有的payara micros向上然后存储
all the measurements from hundreds of
来自数百个的所有测量
devices into any memory data store so
设备存储到任何内存数据中
exactly the same on the server side as
在服务器端与
would be on the mqtt we have what's
会在mqtt上，我们有什么
called a message driven bean it's using
被称为消息驱动的bean
this this case would be as your service
这种情况下将作为您的服务
price will be same with MQTT and we have
价格与MQTT相同，我们有
what's called a cache okay so in a
所谓的缓存好吧，所以在
similar way when it receives a message
收到消息时的类似方法
it basically takes that humidity message
它基本上吸收了湿度信息
measurement from the message creates a
消息中的度量创建一个
new collection with keyed on the sensor
传感器上有钥匙的新系列
name and then pushes it into the grid
名称，然后将其推入网格
and that that's all the code that we
那就是我们所有的代码
require to keep that measurement against
要求保持该测量
the sensor name in a in memory
内存中的传感器名称
large-scale cloud side memory store and
大型云端存储和
to retrieve them again this could be
再次找回他们，这可能是
used on the device as well jakarta ii
在设备上使用的以及jakarta ii
obviously supports full restful web
显然支持完全宁静的网络
services as well so the code to retrieve
服务以及代码检索
things from that data grid is
该数据网格中的内容是
essentially
实质上
is literally you basically hook it to
从字面上看，您基本上将其挂接到
the same grid and when there's a get
相同的网格，如果有
request passing in the sensor name you
要求传递您的传感器名称
could then retrieve all the data and
然后可以检索所有数据，
send it down to a client device as JSON
将其作为JSON发送到客户端设备
string okay so that's that's a demo if
字符串好吧，那就是一个演示，如果
you like of a real code running on real
您喜欢在真实环境中运行的真实代码
smallish devices so why would you use
较小的设备，为什么要使用
Jakarta EE on these devices like saying
这些设备上的Jakarta EE喜欢说
PI R micro small so it's running in
PI R micro很小，因此可以在
about 30 40 megabytes of JVM heap
大约30 40 MB的JVM堆
obviously you then have a JVM overhead
显然，您将有一个JVM开销
but you could run you could you know
但是你可以跑步，你知道吗
maybe potentially within the future of
可能在未来的将来
Java 9j link and java 10 needs shrink
Java 9j链接和Java 10需要缩减
that down to exactly what you need it
恰好满足您的需求
also comes with a bunch of standard api
还附带了一堆标准的api
so you don't have to learn if you're new
因此您不必学习新手
york no dobry you don't have to learn
约克，你不必学习
any new technology to build for these
为这些建立任何新技术
devices so para micro itself has JPA and
设备，因此para micro本身具有JPA和
it has an embedded database so that
它具有嵌入式数据库，因此
device could use standard JPA database
设备可以使用标准的JPA数据库
if it comes with h2 which is an embedded
如果它带有嵌入式的h2
one to store-and-forward data on just on
一个就可以存储和转发数据
the device locally so you can build web
本地设备，以便您可以建立网络
applications using the standard api's
使用标准api的应用程序
but PI or micro supports you know JSF
但是PI或Micro支持您知道JSF
which would be like little bit
有点像
heavyweight but it supports restful web
重量级，但它支持宁静的网络
services WebSockets HTTP to all the
将WebSockets HTTP服务到所有
things that you would need to build say
你需要建造的东西说
an embedded embedded web application on
嵌入式嵌入式Web应用程序
web console on the device we have JC a
设备上的Web控制台，我们拥有JC
so we can connect to messaging systems
这样我们就可以连接到消息传递系统
to get data off so again we I say we
要获取数据，所以我再次说
have a standard at the box and qtt
在包装盒上有一个标准品，然后按一下
support so you could send data by mqtt
支持，因此您可以通过mqtt发送数据
off the device there are standard
关设备有标准
concurrency api's in Carter EE
Carter EE中的并发API
so we can build very simply asynchronous
因此我们可以非常简单地构建异步
reactive multi-threaded applications
反应性多线程应用程序
using the concurrency api's that come
使用并发API
with java re' to build embedded to about
用Java re'构建嵌入到大约
abet embedded applications CDI is also
abet嵌入式应用程序的CDI也是
standard that as an advanced dependency
作为高级依赖的标准
injection framework so you can use that
注入框架，因此您可以使用它
as well and we also have restful support
以及我们也有不懈的支持
so you can build restful endpoints on
这样您就可以在
the devices to communicate with the
与之通信的设备
device it's supposed jax-rs we have JSON
设备应该是jax-rs，我们有JSON
support so it also has rest client
支持，所以它也有休息客户
support so you could use rest to
支持，以便您可以休息
actually as a client to invoke other
实际上作为客户端来调用其他
services from from off the device so so
来自设备的服务也是如此
is Jakarta relevant to IOT so the answer
雅加达与物联网有关吗
obviously it was yes I'm hoping you know
显然是的，我希望你知道
that we can demonstrate it that these
我们可以证明这些
are small one of the things that we did
只是我们做的一件事
about when we built PI or micro was to
关于我们何时建立PI或微型计算机是为了
bring the Jakarta a stroke java ee to
带给雅加达一个中风的Java EE
new developers basically because it's
新开发者基本上是因为
not a big application server with all
没有所有的大型应用服务器
the heavyweight from the past that you
你过去的重量级人物
would think it's basically as a small
会认为这基本上是一个小
runtime so you could build if you out if
运行时，这样就可以构建
you are java re' developer you can build
您是Java开发人员，可以构建
iot applications running pi or micro so
运行pi或micro so的物联网应用程序
you can build applications on small
您可以在小型平台上构建应用程序
devices like raspberry pi and there are
像树莓派这样的设备，还有
some some fun ones out there that we
一些有趣的东西，我们
know and we know guys got is a remote
知道，我们知道，伙计们是一个遥控器
control car called controlled by rest
控制车叫休息控制
endpoints and running on ro surprised
端点并在ro上运行感到惊讶
but from a serious perspective you can
但是从认真的角度来看，你可以
there's many many probably millions of
有很多可能数以百万计的
Java EE developers in the world that
世界各地的Java EE开发人员
maybe not don't want to learn new API to
也许不想学习新的API
program new devices either IOT or on the
对新设备进行物联网或在
cloud PI or micro is basically designed
云PI或Micro基本上是设计好的
to give those people somewhere
把那些人带到某个地方
you know to build cloud applications
你知道构建云应用程序
build IOT applications using the same
使用相同的构建物联网应用程序
API xeno because the same code can like
API xeno，因为相同的代码可以喜欢
run on that or I can run in a huge cloud
在那上面运行，或者我可以在巨大的云中运行
multi tags and node cluster so so next
多标签和节点集群，所以接下来
steps quite a little bit small on here
这里的脚步相当小
so got a download link on there all the
所以那里有一个下载链接
demo code is on github on that link as
演示代码在github上的链接上
well and have a go I mean that we say
好吧，走吧，我的意思是我们说
all a steps open source so this this
所有步骤都是开源的，所以这
whole whole code for this demo is open
该演示的整个代码是开放的
source and on github yeah any questions
来源和github上的任何问题
so anyone want to have a glow on the
所以任何人都想在
sensors or something so the secret is is
传感器之类的秘密是
actually not a lot of different okay so
其实没有很多不同，好吧
one of the big differences is pay are
最大的区别之一是薪酬
micro servos based has an OSGi runtime
基于微伺服的OSGi运行时
underneath ok Paora micro doesn't we use
好的Paora micro下面不使用
OSGi so it's a bit has a slower overhead
OSGi，所以开销有点慢
because of that the payara server
因此，payara服务器
supports the full java 8 w8 api so
支持完整的Java 8 w8 API，因此
there's someone in here that we don't
这里有人，我们不
support you don't support any of the
支持您不支持任何
legacy old java ee so no need to be 2.1
旧版旧版Java ee，因此无需成为2.1
or any of the old things rich full
或任何丰富的旧事物
server does there's no coop or anything
服务器没有小屋或其他任何东西
on this I on micro and it doesn't
在这个我微，它没有
support doesn't have an embedded JMS
支持没有嵌入式JMS
broker or any of the beaks or things
经纪人或任何喙或东西
that the full server would have but it's
完整的服务器会拥有，但是
exactly the same code other than this
与此完全相同的代码
like a wrapper around it
像它周围的包装纸
we did so yeah we used to have a micro
我们做到了，是的，我们曾经有一个微型
profile only so actually payara micro
仅配置文件，因此实际上payara micro
also supports micro profile 1.3 probably
也可能支持micro profile 1.3
as of like yesterday exigent you release
从昨天开始，您释放
yesterday we'd used to keep it just to
昨天我们习惯于保持
PI our micro profile and actually which
PI我们的微观概况，实际上
was basically only support at the Mike
基本上只有迈克的支持
profile api's we stopped doing it
个人资料api的操作已停止
because the resource difference is not
因为资源差异不是
significant
重大
okay it was a bit so PI our micro on a
好吧，有点PI了
reasonable size computer not on a
大小合理的计算机不在
roughly PI will boot in a couple of
大概PI会启动几个
seconds so IR Mike profile boot lean may
秒，因此IR Mike配置文件启动可能会倾斜
be part one in half seconds and the
在半秒内成为第一部分，
memory usage wasn't really any different
内存使用情况并没有什么不同
so we actually concentrate on just
所以我们实际上专注于
keeping the full set of api's and making
保留完整的api并制作
it as small as possible we could do
它尽可能的小
modularity but it would be a do
模块化，但这是一个做
marketing feature not an engineering
营销功能不是工程
feature so so we haven't bothered okay
功能，所以我们不必担心
thank you very much
非常感谢你
[Applause]
[掌声]